In my previous life, were my parents worried about me?
Just before they died, how did they feel about their son, the shut-in?
I'll never know.
I didn't go to their funeral.
Didn't collect their ashes like a son should.
What the hell was I doing?
I barely loved my parents.
It pressures me to think about how little I cared for them.
I should have been there, right?
Should have gone to the funeral.
Seen their dead faces.
Give them one last goodbye.
If you were gonna die, it should have been for Norn and Aisha.
Not a fake like me.
And then there's Zenith and Lilia.
How could you go and abandon all four of them like this?
They were your everything.
Didn't they mean the world to you?
Damn it, Paul.
What the hell am I supposed to do now?
I need you to tell me.
My boy.
I'm so lucky to have a son like you.
To be honest, I never truly felt like his son.
But Paul Greyrat was always my father.
Hey Rudy, mind if I come in?
Mind if I come in?
I'm so lucky to have a son like you.
To be honest, I never truly felt like his son.
But Paul Greyrat was always my father.
Hey Rudy, mind if I come in?
Of course not.
If you're up to it, maybe we should go for a walk.
Huh?
Just think, this city has loads of magical items you can't find anywhere else.
Why don't we go explore?
Check out the shops like we did the other day?
No thanks.
I'm not in the mood.
Oh, I understand.
Sorry, Master.
I know it's tough.
What happened to Paul and Zenith in there is a real tragedy.
I still fondly remember the five of us living together in Buena Village all those years ago.
Truthfully, those days may have been the happiest in my entire life.
When we go out on adventures, sometimes we end up losing people, even the ones who are closest to us.
It's never easy.
I know.
I've gone through it myself.
Master, I wish you wouldn't lie to me.
Your mother and father are still out there alive and well, aren't they?
You're right.
They're both alive.
It's been a few years since I've seen them at this point, but they seem to be-
Then you don't know anything!
So don't sit there and pretend like you do, okay?
It just occurred to me.
I thought I'd start it over, like I was finally getting it right.
But turns out I was still ignoring everything that actually matters.
Anytime we'd fight, I'd just run away from them.
I just kept making all the same mistakes that I can never take back.
I thought I'd changed.
But in the end, I'm still the same person I've always been.
Of course you're the same person.
Still bursting with talent.
You're still kind, just like Paul and Xenath taught you to be.
You all welcomed me into your home and gave me a place to belong.
Thanks to you three, I learned what the true embrace of a real family felt like.
Sure we weren't blood, but your mom and dad, we're my family too.
We're my family too.
Rudy, please let me feel the weight of the sadness with you.
Please.
I may be small and inadequate, but I'm still your teacher.
I've lived a lot longer and it's given me more time to toughen up.
Believe me, I know the ache of despair.
And I know it hurts, but it can hurt less if you share the pain.
The pain.
Rudy!
Please rest.
For now, just leave everything to your master.
Oh, Rudy, good morning.
Yeah, good morning, master.
So, uh, do you feel any better than you did last night?
I do.
Hey, master.
Would you be okay with me asking a strange question?
Go ahead.
If I felt like a bad son, what should I do now?
Well, I would focus on the family you have left and do right by them.
If Po were still here, I'm certain that's what he would have wanted.
Not to wallow in this.
For your family's sake.
You're right.
Master, thank you for everything.
Sure.
Hey, Roxy, did you?
I'm sorry.
Could you give us a few minutes?
She and I have matters we need to discuss.
You go on ahead and join Miss Lelia.
Yeah, understood.
I'm sorry.
Could you give us a few minutes?
Oh, what can I do?
You go on ahead and join Miss Lelia.
Yeah, understood.
Okay.
Can you tell us somebody that's not the best?
Hey, Roxy, did you…
I'm sorry.
Could you give us a few minutes?
She and I have matters we need to discuss.
You go on ahead and join Miss Lelia.
Yeah.
Understood.
Good morning, Leilia.
Is something the matter, Master Rudeus?
It's just that I'm sorry you've had to care for her without me.
Oh, don't be. This is my duty.
How is she? Any progress?
Well, she doesn't seem to remember anything, but physically she is quite healthy.
No residual impairment otherwise.
Is that so?
She just lost her memory. I guess that's good.
It's not like she's completely brain dead.
Shiera has her own pet theory, that this is a side effect being trapped in the crystal.
Something akin to mana poisoning.
Will she recover?
Well, sir, if Alina Lee speaks the truth, there's little hope for that.
My lady treated me like family for many years.
Now that my lord has passed on, it would be my honor to care for her in this time of need.
Thank you. I'll do whatever I can, too.
That's not necessary.
What?
Please forgive me, sir. I realize I'm overstepping my bounds.
But will you allow me to speak freely, impolite or otherwise at this time?
Please.
From now on, focus on your own duties.
I don't understand. Why?
It's what your father would have wanted.
My duty is right here, at my lady's side.
You have a family now, and they need you.
Let's go home.
They're waiting for us.
You have a family now, and they're waiting for us.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Master, we need to talk.
Yes, of course, Rudy. What is it?
Let's be honest. I love Roxy.
Not in quite the same way I love Sylphie, but I couldn't tell you who I love more.
So I'm torn. I love my wife, and I love my master.
But I gave Sylphie my word that I'd stay faithful. I can't betray that.
You deserve to know. Before all this happened, I actually got married.
In fact, we have a child on the way.
So I'm... I'm really sorry for giving you any false hope.
But romance isn't really...
I know all that. After your dad passed away, and we were all worried about your well-being,
Alina Lise told me a lot about your life.
Really? Then why?
Please don't blame yourself. You were so upset.
I took advantage of the situation to help us both feel a little better.
It was entirely my decision.
And besides, if you had the choice, I know you wouldn't normally go for someone like me.
It's not like that.
Don't worry. I have no plans to barge into your life. I'll just be your left hand.
And then once we get back home, you can give your wife all your devotion.
If that's what you want. Can I at least repay you, though?
You want to repay me? For what?
Well, for everything that you've done for me.
Huh? I see. All right, then. Would you like to start by listening to my excuse?
Um, excuse for what?
All you have to do is listen.
Okay. Please, go ahead.
I fell in love at first sight.
With whom?
With you, Rudy. The very moment you came to my rescue in the labyrinth.
Really?
Why are you surprised? An entrance like that would make anyone's heart race.
You were the picture of my ideal partner the entire time we were down there.
I couldn't take my eyes off of you.
You wouldn't even look me in the eye, though.
I know. Can you blame me? I was nervous.
I thought the whole thing was hopeless.
And then once we got back to the inn,
Elena, Lisa, and Geese thought you'd be fine on your own.
But I remembered what you were like as a kid in Buena.
Uh, of course I had been told that you shared your life with someone you love.
And if you felt broken, I knew she'd have the power to lift you back up.
Only, she wasn't here when you needed her most.
So, I felt like someone had to save you.
Even if Elena, Lisa, and Geese thought it best to leave you alone.
And poor Lelia.
I knew she wouldn't have the time or energy,
since she had her hands full with zenith.
So, to ease your pain, I did what I thought was right.
In the end, I couldn't help it.
I love you.
I was being selfish.
I should have loved you alone.
Master, listen to me.
What is it?
While we're here, at least before we make it home.
No.
What good will that do?
It doesn't solve anything.
Not for me, and certainly not for Roxy.
That's enough.
I'll be fine.
I don't need you to do anything.
Okay, I'll stop.
You can remove your blindfolds now.
We've made it outside.
Rudy, where are we?
We're in a forest near Sharia.
I can't believe it.
We've really made it to the Northlands already?
Now I get it, boss.
I see how you got to Rapun so fast.
Whatever you do, don't tell anyone about this place.
Sure thing.
Okay.
Elina, Lys, and I will take the lead from here.
Rudeus?
What's up?
Your faith.
You're not a worshiper of Mili's now, are you?
I never have been.
And would it be safe to assume that Sylphie isn't either?
Yeah, that'd be a safe bet.
As you know, my dear Cliff is a devout follower.
Mm-hmm.
What you may not know is that followers of Mili's are only allowed to take one wife.
It's meant to be a lifelong commitment, and they are to remain faithful to her till death do they part.
It's a bit strict.
It's a bit strict, but now that I'm on the receiving end, I must admit I rather enjoy it.
That being said, in my opinion, there is absolutely nothing wrong with loving more than one partner at the same time.
I'm not surprised, but what exactly are you trying to say?
To be clear, I think you should marry Roxy.
Are you being serious right now?
Yes.
With every fiber of me, no one else could mean it like I do.
Frankly, I can't stand to see Roxy like this.
The poor girl.
She yearns to throw herself into the relationship with you, but she's forcing herself to hold back just because she met you at the wrong time.
I want Roxy to have a modest share of happiness.
At the very least, she deserves that.
Yeah, but what about Sylphie?
What do you plan to do about Roxy, then?
Of course, I want her to be happy, too.
I want that for both of them.
It's just that I made a promise.
How selfish can I be?
I married Sylphie.
We have a kid on the way.
And now I want another woman, too?
To think all those times I've called Paul a scumbag, and now I'm sitting here contemplating the same thing.
What about Paul and Lelia?
After their affair and subsequent marriage, did Zenith become miserable?
No, other than some tears and resentment at first.
Well, sure, that much goes without saying.
I know you've got it in you.
You can love Sylphie and Roxy all the same, boy.
You're Paul's flesh and blood.
He must be at least good for that, wouldn't you agree?
Maybe so.
I genuinely love them both.
But what would Sylphie think if I came home with a lover?
And what about Roxy?
She might want me all to herself.
Or what if they both dump me and I wind up alone again?
I want to be able to give them the lives they deserve.
I guess.
But even if I want to go through with it, they'd both have to be in agreement, and that might be a different story altogether.
In that case, you should find out what Roxy's feelings are, huh?
Look.
Hey.
What do you want to talk about?
Master...
This is something I've wanted to say for a long time.
Okay.
Throughout my adventures, your teachings saved my life.
Without your influence, I wouldn't have made it this far.
So, I guess...
Well, here's the thing.
I'm married to someone dear to me.
Her name's Sylphiet Greyrat, and we're expecting a child.
I know. We talked about it.
What the hell am I trying to say here?
My, uh...
My wife...
She didn't used to have a family name.
She was always just Sylphiet.
Yes. I'm aware of that, too.
That's not what I wanted to say at all!
Oh, fine.
Being a scumbag beats looking back and wishing I'd said more.
Sure, right?
Master Roxy, would you ever consider changing your full name to Roxy Greyrat?
Uh...
I love you, too.
I'm grateful to hear you say that.
Truly, I am.
But...
A decision like this would require your wife's approval.
Without a doubt, yes.
Well, then...
No.
But please ask again what she's given it.
Uh...
I...
Okay.
What do you know?
We're the same.
That one...
The Saucong...
I love you.
My mom.
Be sure to fit.
You know?
Go get her born.
Come Wam.
Come.
I love you.
What do you know?
You know how I truly meet you.
How do you know how to do the right thing?
La-ya-la-ya-la